expedia.com.au 2009-12-13

# Expedia Privacy Pledge

* * *

This site is operated by Expedia of 3150 139th Avenue SE, Bellevue, Washington 98005 United States of America.   
Expedia, Inc. and its related bodies corporate (“Expedia” or “we”) are bound by and comply with the National Privacy Principles set out in Schedule 3 to the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) in relation to the collection and disclosure of information regarding individuals in Australia.   
We understand that making purchases online involves a great deal of trust on your part; we take this trust very seriously, and make it our highest priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personally identifiable information ("PII") you provide us. (PII includes information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as name, address, phone number, or email address.) 

As a visitor to Expedia's Australian Web site, www.Expedia.com.au ("Expedia.com.au"), you have the right to understand our information privacy practices prior to providing Expedia, Inc. or its related bodies corporate, suppliers or distributors with any of your PII. 

**What information we collect**  
Expedia only collects PII that you **voluntarily** provide to us.   
Tell me more.

**How we use your information**  
Expedia uses your PII only for the purpose of responding to and fulfilling your requests made by use of Expedia.com.au.   
Tell me more.

**Who we share your information with**  
Expedia will only share your PII with our authorised travel service providers, and only as necessary in order to complete a transaction that you specifically request. **Expedia does not sell or rent your PII to anyone.**   
Tell me more.

**How you can control the use of your information**  
Expedia provides you with choice and control over the collection and use of your PII, as well as a means of updating, correcting, or removing any PII stored in your customer profile.   
Tell me more.

**How you can decide what marketing communications you'll receive**  
Expedia provides you with the opportunity to specifically choose the promotional marketing communications you wish to receive from Expedia. If you choose not to receive any of the promotional email services that Expedia.com.au provides, then Expedia will only send you email that relates to a specific travel purchase you have made on Expedia.com.au.   
Tell me more.

**How we protect your information**  
To ensure the confidentiality of your PII, Expedia uses leading security technology and procedures.   
Tell me more.

By providing you with this Privacy Statement, Expedia is pledging our continued commitment to protecting the information you provide us.

**Expedia Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement discloses the information privacy practices for Expedia with respect to the Expedia.com.au web site. The Expedia.com.au Web site is intended for use by residents of Australia that are over 18 years of age. 

**Information collected about you**  
Expedia collects Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") about you that you specifically and voluntarily provide. PII includes information that can identify you as a specific individual, such as your name, phone number, or e-mail address. Although you are required to register as a member of Expedia in order to use selected travel planning tools, and some PII is needed in order to process and fulfill travel requests, many areas of Expedia can be accessed without providing any PII. 

On all Expedia.com.au pages that collect PII, we specifically describe what information is required in order to provide you with the product or service you have requested. 

At present, Expedia centralises its records of PII for all Expedia operations, including those on Expedia.com.au, in the United States. As a consequence Expedia may perform some of its data processing of your PII outside Australia , for example in the United States. To do this, Expedia may transfer your PII internationally to other countries including the United States. Some of the countries may have laws that protect your PII, some may not. Expedia will protect your PII no matter where we process or store your data by following this privacy statement. By becoming a member of Expedia.com.au you give your consent to this transfer of your PII.

Expedia collects PII via Expedia.com.au when you: 

  * Become a Expedia.com.au member 
  * Complete a traveller profile 
  * Purchase travel 
  * Use the Travel Arranger service 
  * Participate in a survey, contest, or sweepstakes 
  * Contact Expedia.com.au 

**Member information**   
Expedia collects your Member ID, password, and e-mail address when you register to become a member of our Expedia.com.au Web site. 

**Traveller profile information**   
Expedia collects the full name and contact number for a traveller when a travel reservation is made on Expedia.com.au. We may also collect information about each traveler's preferences, including meal requests, seat selection, frequent flyer/hotel/car hire programmes and membership numbers, and ticketing options. This information is stored in the  My Profile area of a member's Expedia.com.au account. 

When someone other than yourself is accompanying you on travel purchased through Expedia.com.au, we may collect PII and travel preferences about that individual. You should obtain the consent of other individuals prior to providing Expedia with their full names, contact numbers, and travel preferences, as they will be unable to directly access our systems to view or change any information you provide on their behalf (however, they may submit a written request to us to access any PII you provide to us on their behalf.)   

**Access to your information**  
We will, on request, provide you with access to the PII we hold about you, unless there is an exception which applies under the National Privacy Principles as set out in Schedule 3 to the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). We may recover from you our reasonable costs of supplying you with access to this PII and your request to provide access to this PII will be dealt with in a reasonable time. If we refuse to provide you with access to the PII, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal and inform you of any exceptions relied upon under the National Privacy Principles. 

**Travel purchase information**   
Expedia collects the billing address of the credit card that is used to purchase travel through Expedia.com.au. We will also collect credit card information, including card number, card type, cardholder name, and expiry date, in order to bill you for some of the travel purchased through Expedia.com.au. Please view our  Credit Card Guarantee for additional information on Expedia , Inc. and its related bodies corporate’s commitment to protecting your credit card security. 

**Travel Arranger information**   
Expedia.com.au offers you the ability to authorise others to make and purchase travel arrangements on your behalf and allows you to become an authorised Travel Arranger for other Expedia.com.au members. If you elect to participate in this service, Expedia will collect the email address of the person you are authorising to make travel arrangements on your behalf or for whom you are requesting authorisation to make travel arrangements. 

**Surveys, contests, and sweepstakes**   
Occasionally, Expedia may offer our members and site visitors an opportunity to participate in a survey, contest, or sweepstakes. Information collected by Expedia when you participate in a survey, contest, or sweepstakes may include your full name, e-mail address, and street address. 

**Contacting Expedia.com.au**   
Expedia collects PII such as your full name, Member ID, email address, and/or contact number whenever you submit a question or suggestion, or request assistance with viewing your itinerary, logging on to Expedia.com.au, or accessing your account. 

**Our partners**   
Expedia has partnered with reputable third parties to offer our members and site visitors a variety of products and services. All travel services throughout Expedia.com.au that are provided by a third-party partner are described as such. Although we only work with reputable third parties, our business partners may have different privacy policies and practices than Expedia . We encourage you to review our business partners' privacy policies to further understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing your information. 

**Other information we collect**   
Some information is collected automatically every time you visit Expedia.com.au. Expedia collects information about your computer and assigns you a "cookie" (a small, unique identifier text file) when you visit Expedia.com.au. You do not provide this information—it is collected automatically as a means of supporting your visit to our site. This cookie does not contain any PII. Click here to find out more about cookies.

**Cookies and other Web technologies**   
As a member or visitor to Expedia.com.au you will be assigned a permanent cookie file on your computer's hard drive. You can always choose to not receive a cookie file by enabling your Web browser to refuse cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie. Be advised that, by refusing to accept a cookie, you will not be able to access many travel services and planning tools offered on Expedia.com.au. 

When you access the  My Trips or  My Profile areas of the Expedia.com.au Web site, reserve or purchase travel, or use selected travel planning tools, Expedia requires you to sign in as a member, using your Member ID and password. Once you sign in as an Expedia.com.au member, we record the Member ID and the name on the member account in the cookie file on your computer. We may also record your password in this cookie file if you checked the box entitled "Save this password for automatic sign-in." Your Member ID, password, and the name on your member account is stored in the cookie file as encrypted data, so no one can view the information it contains by obtaining unauthorized access to your computer. Permanent cookie files remain on your computer's hard drive until you manually delete the file. 

The third-party advertising companies may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of ads. This is primarily accomplished through the use of an action tag (also known as an invisible gif), which the third party places on our site to collect anonymous information. They may use this anonymous information about your visits to this and other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of potential interest to you. No PII is collected during this process. The information is anonymous and does not link online actions to an identifiable person. 

**Computer information**   
Expedia collects certain technical information from your computer each time you request a page during a visit to Expedia.com.au. This information is collected from your computer's Web browser and may include your IP address, operating system, Web browser software (e.g. Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer), screen resolution, and referrer Web site. Wireless users: Please check with your wireless company if you are using your cellular phone to access the Internet to understand whether PII may be used to identify you. 

**Failure to provide information**

When making travel plans or a purchase using Expedia.com.au you must provide the requested contact information and financial information. We will use your contact information to reserve the required services, to send you details of the confirmation, for billing purposes and to inform you of any updates or changes to your travel plans. 

If you do not provide the requested contact information and financial information we may not be able to complete your requests or orders and you may not be able to access all areas of Expedia.com.au.

**Use of your information**  
Information collected on Expedia.com.au may be used to: 

  * Register you as an Expedia.com.au member 
  * Plan and purchase travel 
  * Notify you on travel changes through the Travel Alerts service
  * Send email notifications for special promotions
  * Respond to your questions or suggestions 
  * Improve the quality of your visit to our site 

**Member Registration Information**   
When you register to become a member of Expedia.com.au, we use your information to create your member account. You will then receive a "Welcome to Expedia.com.au" email that contains your Member ID and describes the benefits of using Expedia.com.au for planning and purchasing your travel needs. 

**Travel planning and purchase**   
Information collected when you complete your traveller profile is used to confirm and process your travel reservation. In addition, information collected from you when you purchase travel is used to bill your credit card and deliver your travel itinerary, either electronically or through the mail. 

**Travel Alerts notification**   
In the event your travel plans are disrupted because of mechanical, weather, or carrier business conditions, Expedia may send you an email notification to inform you of these conditions and help you make alternative travel arrangements. 

**E-mail notifications**   
If you chose to receive communications from Expedia.com.au about special promotions when registering as an Expedia.com.au member, we may use your e-mail address to send you communications about surveys, contests, sweepstakes, promotions, flight specials, or other travel opportunities on Expedia.com.au and its marketing partners. We may use your e-mail address or telephone number to contact you about changes to your purchased travel itinerary. 

We want to make it easy for you to take advantage of travel-related opportunities on our website. One way we do this is by reviewing your purchasing and browsing behaviour to indentify and present e-mail messages that contain information about your apparent travel-related interests. For example, if you search for a flight to New York on our Web site and save this to your itinerary, we may send you an email message reminding you about your saved travel itinerary or about a special airfare to New York. Similarly, if you receive an email from us about New York travel and demonstrate an interest in New York hotels by affirmatively clicking on a link about New York hotels in the e-mail, you may receive an email about New York hotel offers. We believe these e-mail messages will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our sites. Please note that you will have the opportunity to choose not to receive these e-mail messages in any such email we send. 

**Responses to your questions or suggestions**   
We will use your e-mail address or telephone number to respond when you submit a question or suggestion, or request assistance with viewing your itinerary, logging on to Expedia.com.au, or accessing your account. 

**Improving the quality of your visit to our site**   
We collect information about your computer (not your name, address, email address, or telephone number) through your permanent cookie file for the purpose of assessing the effectiveness of site content and traffic. This data allows us to improve the quality of your visit by streamlining your ability to navigate the site and develop featured programmes and content that will be of interest to our members and site visitors. 

**Sharing your information**  
Expedia.com.au does not sell or rent your PII to anyone. 

**Service providers**   
We only provide information about travel either reserved or purchased on Expedia.com.au to third parties that provide services or functions on behalf of Expedia. Our service providers need information about your traveller profile, as well as your credit card information, to process and confirm your travel reservation. These service providers will disclose information about your traveller profile to hotel, airline, and/or car hire suppliers whose products you have purchased. Like any other travel agent, this information must be shared with our travel suppliers to confirm your reservation and travel preferences. Although Expedia facilitates purchases travel products from hotel, airline, and car hire suppliers that are reputable companies, we have not placed limitations on these suppliers from using or disclosing your information without your permission. Therefore, we encourage you to review the information privacy practices of any travel suppliers whose products you purchase on Expedia.com.au. In addition, these travel suppliers may also contact you as necessary to obtain additional information about your confirmed reservation. 

Expedia will occasionally share aggregated information with our service providers whose products or services are offered through Expedia.com.au. This information does not contain any PII and is used to develop featured programmes and content that will be of interest to our members and site visitors. 

In the event that you make a new, or update an existing, travel reservation by calling our call centre number, your information may be accessed by a third-party service provider, as necessary, to respond to your request for customer service. 

Expedia may contract a reputable third-party to facilitate the distribution of survey, promotion, or sweepstake programmes. Upon completion of these projects, all information is returned to Expedia. 

**Our legal obligations**

Expedia may be required by law to disclose information you have provided in obtaining travel products or services in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary (a) to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Expedia or the site; (b) where Expedia  has reason to suspect that unlawful activity has been, is being or may be engaged in, as part of its investigation of the matter or in [reporting](http://www.austlii.edu.au/au/legis/cth/consol_act/pa1988108/s18n.html#report) its concerns to relevant persons or authorities in relation to the property of Expedia, and (c) to act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Expedia, the site or the public. 

Under U.S. Law, U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) will receive some of your travel and reservation information, known as Passenger Name Record or PNR data, about passengers flying between the European Union and the U.S.A.

CBP has undertaken that it uses this PNR data for the purposes of preventing and combating terrorism and other transnational serious crimes. The PNR may include information provided during the booking process or held by airlines or travel agents. The information will be retained for at least three years and six months and may be shared with other authorities. For further information about these arrangements, including measures to safeguard your PII, see: <http://www.dhs.gov/interweb/assetlibrary/CBP-DHS_PNRUndertakings5-25-04.pdf>

We may also disclose your PII to various other law enforcement agencies and governments around the world for security, customs and immigration purposes.

**Other Web sites**   
There are several places throughout Expedia.com.au that may link you to other Web sites that do not operate under Expedia.com.au information privacy practices. When you click through to these Web sites, Expedia information privacy practices no longer apply. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements for all third party Web sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing your information. 

**Control over and access to your information**  
Expedia believes that members and site visitors should have control over the collection and use of their PII. You have access to your information in the following areas of Expedia.com.au: 

**My Account**   
The   My Account  page on Expedia allows members to view and change their account settings. The email settings option lets you change your email address and subscribe or unsubscribe to the special promotional notification services. You can also change your password and elect to have an automatic password sign-in when logging on to Expedia.com.au. You can add new travellers and delete existing travellers from your member profile; update or correct names, phone numbers, passport information, and emergency contacts for travellers associated with your profile; and update your travel preferences.  

You can also close your Expedia.com.au account by selecting the   Account Closure option. Once you close an account, you will not be able to sign in or access any information associated with the account, but you can open a new account at any time. We will send you an e-mail confirming your account closure to the e-mail address contained in your member profile. 

**My Itineraries**   
The   My Itineraries page on Expedia.com.au allows members to view, update, or delete their saved itineraries. 

**Communications from Expedia.com.au**  
Members will receive communications from Expedia.com.au when they: 

  * Sign-up to become an Expedia.com.au member 
  * Request to close an account 
  * Purchase travel 
  * Elect to receive Fare special promotional marketing communications 
  * Win a contest or sweepstake 
  * Contact Expedia.com.au with questions/suggestions 

**Sign-up to become a Expedia.com.au member**   
When you sign up as a new Expedia.com.au member, you will receive a "Welcome to Expedia.com.au" e-mail. This e-mail contains your member ID and describes the benefits of using Expedia.com.au for planning and purchasing your travel needs. 

**Request to close an account**   
When you complete an Account Closure request, we will send you an "Account Closure Confirmation" e-mail. 

**Purchase Travel**   
Each time you purchase travel through Expedia.com.au, or change or cancel a confirmed travel reservation, you will receive confirmation of your travel itinerary via e-mail. In the event that your travel plans are disrupted because of mechanical, weather, or carrier business conditions, Expedia may contact you to inform you of these disruptions and help you make alternative travel arrangements. 

**Elect to receive special promotional marketing communications**   
As a registered Expedia.com.au member, you will occasionally receive e-mails notifying you of special promotions or other travel news, if you sign up for this service when you register. Special promotional e-mails are intended to inform you of new or unique travel opportunities or special deals that are available on Expedia.com.au.If you have purchased travel services, you may also receive an email that provides information about your destination, such as weather conditions, current events, or items of interest.   

You can discontinue your subscription to Expedia.com.au's promotional email services at any time on the  My Profile page under the heading "Email settings." You can also unsubscribe to special promotional emails at any time by replying to the email with the word "unsubscribe" in the subject line. 

**Request customer support or submit questions/suggestions**   
When you request assistance with viewing your itinerary, logging on to the Expedia.com.au site, or accessing your account, we will respond to you via e-mail or telephone. 

**Protecting your information**  
We want our members and site visitors to feel confident about using Expedia.com.au to plan and purchase their travel, so we are committed to protecting the information we collect. Expedia has implemented a security programme to keep information that is stored in our systems protected from unauthorized access. Currently, Expedia only stores the information you provide when registering to become an Expedia.com.au member, create a travel profile, purchase travel, or use selected travel tools. 

Our systems are configured with data encryption, or scrambling, technologies, and industry-standard firewalls. When you send personal information to Expedia over the Internet, your data is protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure safe transmission. 

Expedia has also obtained a digital certificate from RSA Data Security, Inc., a top maker of hardware and software used to protect and manage computer network access. To view this site certificate on each secured page, click on the image of the closed lock or the solid key on the bottom bar of your browser window. A small frame displaying site security information will pop up. 

  * For Internet Explorer users: Click on the word "Subject" to verify that you are on the Web site www.Expedia.com.au. Click on "Issuer" to verify the site certification authority. 
  * For Netscape Communicator users: Click on "View Certificate" to verify that you are on the Web site www.Expedia.com.au and to verify the site certification authority. 

**Changes to the Expedia.com.au Privacy Statement**  
Expedia reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Statement at any time and for any reason. If there are material changes to this statement or in how Expedia.com.au will use your PII, Expedia.com.au will prominently display such changes prior to implementing the change. 

Regardless of later updates, we will abide by the information privacy practices described in this Privacy Statement at the time you provided us with your information. 

If you have questions about our Privacy Statement, please  [e-mail us](mailto:travel@support.expedia.com.au). 

**Contacting Expedia.com.au**  
We want to make sure you have control over your online travel experience as an Expedia.com.au customer, from planning and purchasing your travel to protecting your personal information. 

If you wish to gain access to your personal information, have a complaint about a breach of your privacy or you have any query on how your personal information is collected, used or disclosed please call 1300 EXPEDIA (1300 397 3342) or +61 3 9639 5154 for calls outside Australia or from outside Australia on +61 1300 EXPEDIA (1300 397 3342) or +61 3 9639 5154 for calls outside Australia (usual costs apply) from 9am - 7pm Monday to Friday, and 9am - 1pm on Saturdays to speak to a representative personally.

Expedia customer service agents are ready to help with your Expedia travel concerns. When you need help, use our feedback form. All email receives a response within 24 hours. You may also call 1300 EXPEDIA (1300 397 3342) or +61 3 9639 5154 for calls outside Australia or from outside Australia on +61 1300 EXPEDIA (1300 397 3342) or +61 3 9639 5154 for calls outside Australia (usual costs apply) from 9am - 7pm Monday to Friday, and 9am - 1pm on Saturdays to speak to a representative personally. Agents will address any questions or concerns you may have about your Expedia.com.au travel planning or purchases. We will do our best to respond to your request for assistance or other questions about Expedia.com.au within 24 hours.

In addition, you may directly contact the travel supplier at the phone number or address provided on your travel itinerary. 

This Privacy Statement was updated and posted on Expedia.com.au on 20 September 2009.
